<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Social Good - EPFL - ADA</title>
    <description>Society is demanding that companies, both public and private, serve a social purpose. To prosper over time, every company must not only deliver financial performance but also show how it makes a positive contribution to society. 
 - Laurence D. Fink, CEO BlackRock</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 11:59:33 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Dec 2018 11:59:33 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Who owns Who?</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This first substory aims to show the general information we were able to extract from the SEC dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/cgi-bin/browse-edgar?company=&amp;amp;CIK=&amp;amp;type=13F&amp;amp;owner=include&amp;amp;count=40&amp;amp;action=getcurrent&quot;&gt;SEC asset manager portfolios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-question&quot;&gt;Research Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What asset managers have the portfolios with the greatest/least social impact?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;general-overview-and-cleaning&quot;&gt;General Overview and Cleaning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;![alt text][../img/results_plots/download-1.png]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2017-investor-portfolios-by-social-impact&quot;&gt;2017 Investor Portfolios by Social Impact&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//plot.ly/~mike.jiao/10.embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2-D Scatterplot focus in on year 2017 data from the previous 3-D scatterplot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The lowest scoring investor, Akanthos Capital Management, is focused on a very specialized investment strategy (event-driven investing), which operates independently of long-term social trends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//assets/2018/12/15/project-4/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//assets/2018/12/15/project-4/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Assets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Asset Manager's Portfolio</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction--definitions&quot;&gt;Introduction &amp;amp; Definitions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS), a &lt;strong&gt;financial asset&lt;/strong&gt; can be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash or cash equivalent,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Equity instruments of another entity,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contractual right to receive cash or another financial asset from another entity or to exchange financial assets or financial liabilities with another entity under conditions that are potentially favourable to the entity,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A contract that will or may be settled in the entity’s own equity instruments and is either a non-derivative for which the entity is or may be obliged to receive a variable number of the entity’s own equity instruments, or a derivative that will or may be settled other than by exchange of a fixed amount of cash or another financial asset for a fixed number of the entity’s own equity instruments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sec.gov/cgi-bin/browse-edgar?company=&amp;amp;CIK=&amp;amp;type=13F&amp;amp;owner=include&amp;amp;count=40&amp;amp;action=getcurrent&quot;&gt;SEC asset manager portfolios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-questions&quot;&gt;Research Questions&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What are the most popular “ethical” or “unethical” investments held by asset managers?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;popularity-of-high-social-impact-stocks&quot;&gt;Popularity of High Social Impact Stocks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//plot.ly/~mike.jiao/12.embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The heatmap shows the most and least popular “ethical” investments held by asset managers. It shows the number of investors in 2017 for each stock that scored within the top 10% of Just Capital Social Impact stocks, where stocks scoring in the top 10% of Just Capital Social Impact scores are labeled “ethical”. 
Said slightly differently, the heatmap displays the social impact (scored by Just Capital) of each stock within the top 10% of Just Capital Social Impact Scores, as well as the number of large institutional investors (with at least 100M in US 13F type securities) that own that stock. 
More popular stocks are represented by lighter colours, whereas less popular stocks are represented with darker colours. 
Although the top 10% of Just Capital Social Impact Scores corresponds to 87 stocks, only 43 stocks are shown in this heatmap. This is because half of these stocks are not held by any large asset manager investor. 
Notice that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Technology companies, as an industry category, are the most popular “ethical” investments held by asset managers. A large number of stocks shown in this plot represent technology companies, including Apple (APPL) with a social impact score of 59.97005 and 1181 large asset manager investors, and Microsoft (MSFT) with a social impact score of 68.55428 and 948 large asset manager investors.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blue Chip stocks such as Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson (JNJ) with a social impact score of 59.94658 and 833 large asset manager investors, and Nike (NKE) also appear.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Even with a range of stock social impact scores from 53 to 70, few stocks have scores higher than 63&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;popularity-of-low-social-impact-stocks&quot;&gt;Popularity of Low Social Impact Stocks&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heatmap shows the most and least popular “unethical” investments held by asset managers. Correspond to bottom 10% of Just Capital Social Impact Scores. 
Notice that:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Large asset manager investors in general hold far fewer stocks in this category
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;each stock has a lower number of investors&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;there are also less stocks displayed compared to the top ethical stocks&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many stocks (80%) in the bottom 10% of Just Capital Social Impact Scores are not held by any large asset manager investors&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interesting to find Tesla (TSLA) with a score of 45.05744 and 66 large asset manager investors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//assets/2018/12/14/project-2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//assets/2018/12/14/project-2/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Assets</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Towards Social Good</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-question&quot;&gt;Research Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Was there a transition toward investing more into social good then into other projects? If yes, when did it happen?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;portfolio-social-impact-by-investor-and-year&quot;&gt;Portfolio Social Impact by Investor and Year&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//plot.ly/~dcleres/23.embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3-D scatterplot shows the portfolio-wide social impact of institutional investors with over 100M in holders in a sample of three years between 2013 and 2018 (2013, 2015, and 2017). Portfolio-wide social impact is measured using a score computed as a weighted average of a portfolio’s individual stocks’ social impact. The score is computed using the portfolio weight percentage of each stock declared in SEC 13F filings, and individual stock social impact scores computed by Just Capital. 
Observations include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investors do not seem to be, as a general trend, shifting towards higher social impact investments&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very few investors have relatively high social impact scores, with the majority of investors having relatively much lower scores&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highest portfolio social impact score:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Mirae Asset Global Investments (2013) - 400B Korean Financial Services Group&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Rehmann Capital Advisory Group (2015) - Wealth Management Advisory (high networth individuals)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;AETNA INC /PA/ (2017) - Healthcare Company&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lowest portfolio social impact score (all scores of 0):
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/research/stocks/private/snapshot.asp?privcapId=133257895&quot;&gt;Index Management Solutions, LLC (2013)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://waterinv.com/&quot;&gt;Water Asset Management, LCC (2015)&lt;/a&gt; - Land and Buildings Investment Management, LCC (2017)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Notice that these investors are all relatively small, LLC, specialized investors focused on very specific verticals such as Water Storage, Real Estate, and investment services&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;investor-social-impact-in-2013-vs-2017&quot;&gt;Investor Social Impact in 2013 vs 2017&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//plot.ly/~mike.jiao/25.embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Scatterplot displays how the social impact of investor portfolios has changed from 2013 to 2017. The graph has 5 layers/traces that can be optionally displayed or removed from the plot by clicking the respective item in the Legend. 
These layers in order from top to bottom correspond with 1) All 2017 Investor Portfolio Social Impact Scores, 2) 2017 
Investor Portfolio Social Impact Scores for the top 10% of Investors by Portfolio Social Impact Score from 2013, 3) 2017 
Investor Portfolio Social Impact Scores for the bottom 10% of Investors by Portfolio Social Impact Score from 2013, 4) 2013 Investor Portfolio Social Impact Scores for the top 10% of Investors by Portfolio Social Impact Score in 2017, and 5) 2013 Investor Portfolio Social Impact Scores for the bottom 10% of Investors by Portfolio Social Impact Score in 2017.
Using these different layers, you can see how the Social Impact of the best and worst Social Impact Investors has changed, or not changed between 2013 and 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems like while a small minority of investors have adopted specialized strategies towards increasing social impact, most have not decided that predominantly social impact oriented portfolios related to successful investment returns. There does not seem to be an overall transition towards social impact investing. Although we can definitely see that the the largest, most successful investors are not among the worst at investing for social impact, this may be due to for example owning larger numbers of successful technology company stocks such as Apple and Microsoft that also tend to have produced incredibly high financial returns, instead of deliberate efforts to adopt investment portfolios that are more socially impactful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//history/2018/12/12/project-7/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//history/2018/12/12/project-7/</guid>
        
        
        <category>History</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Ethics of Investing</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;introduction-to-the-ethical-puzzle&quot;&gt;Introduction to the Ethical Puzzle&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the definition of ethical investing could be stated as simply purchasing investments from issuers who act ethically, investors who seek to achieve this must first establish a set of criteria that can be used to determine what actions and practices are considered ethical to them. For example, the Bible and other religious books provide rules and principles for people to live by, and those who believe what those books say use them as guides to evaluate things in the world around them. Religious texts and other moral teachings, however, do not always provide crystal-clear guidance for practical investment decisions.
Although creating or finding the ethical criteria to use as the basis for evaluating investments may often be relatively simple, effectively applying that criteria to actual investment choices can be more difficult. For instance, the Bible condemns drunkenness in several passages, but does this then make it unconditionally wrong to purchase securities issued by makers of alcoholic beverages? Since not all consumers of alcohol get drunk, then the investor will have to decide for him or herself whether this investment truly supports immoral behavior. Virtually all issuers of securities or investments most likely do something that at least a substantial percentage of their investors do not approve of (how many investors who buy Treasury securities approve of everything that is done by the government?). Of course, this begs the question of which practices and policies are tolerable for investors and which are not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ethical Issues
Although the values and beliefs that guide ethically minded investors differ somewhat for each person, there are several specific areas where ethics play a major role. Some of the more notable issues that investors examine from an ethical standpoint include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Winning at Someone Else’s Expense
Although there will inevitably be both winners and losers in a free-market economy, the issue of how a company wins is a concern to some. Companies that have monopolies in a market or industry can function very efficiently in many respects, but they also effectively prevent any form of healthy business competition, and some investors consider this to be unethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Environmental Responsibility
Heavy industry such as energy and manufacturing have long been perceived as destroyers of nature and wildlife with their pollution and decimation of forests, oceans, lakes and rivers. Ethical investors favor companies that replace what they take from the earth and adhere to governmental standards for emissions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abortion and Stem-Cell Research
Companies that profit from certain medical procedures or types of research are often considered to be unethical or even criminal by those in the Judeo-Christian community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Sin” Industries
Although the concept of an industry being sinful is obviously somewhat subjective, a portion of the investing public still considers makers of alcoholic beverages, tobacco companies, casinos and the pornography industry to be taboo. The tobacco industry, for instance, has long been accused of targeting teenagers as customers and making its products as addictive as possible in order to fuel sales. While sin industries have made efforts to raise public awareness of the dangers of misusing their products and services, some investors may choose to avoid companies that operate in these industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Socially Conscious Investing
Many investors who seek to avoid what they consider to be unethical investments look to vehicles such as socially conscious mutual funds that screen companies according to specific ethically-based criteria. Many such funds are offered by religious denominations such as the Lutheran Brotherhood, which typically avoids investing in any of the “sin” industries listed above and can provide investors with a clear conscience in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-question&quot;&gt;Research Question&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//ethics/2018/12/11/project-1/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//ethics/2018/12/11/project-1/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Ethics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sentiment Analysis</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt; The raw dataset was composed of all the tweets from 2017. Since the focus of this section was to link feelings that customers 
                 express on Twitter regarding companies through time. For this reason, the twitter data was sampled in 10-days intervals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-question&quot;&gt;Research Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to map news article sentiments to specific investments held by companies?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//sentiments/2018/12/10/project-3/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//sentiments/2018/12/10/project-3/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Sentiments</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Investment Geography</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Used Dataset:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;research-question&quot;&gt;Research Question&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the most ethical assets?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;libraries--methods&quot;&gt;Libraries &amp;amp; Methods&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;choices-mades&quot;&gt;Choices Mades&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;900&quot; height=&quot;800&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;//plot.ly/~dcleres/21.embed&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;discussion&quot;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//geography/2018/12/01/project-6/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//geography/2018/12/01/project-6/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Geography</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Other Countries</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;coming-soon&quot;&gt;Coming Soon&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//outreach/2014/07/14/project-5/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/investing_for_social_good//outreach/2014/07/14/project-5/</guid>
        
        
        <category>outreach</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
